A Major Ocean Picture
Surf's Up is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Ash Brannon.
A young surfer enters his first contest, hoping a win will earn him respect.
But an encounter with a laid-back local forces him to rethink his values.
Cody Maverick (voice), played by Shia LaBeouf.
Big Z / Geek (voice), played by Jeff Bridges.
Lani Aliikai (voice), played by Zooey Deschanel.
Chicken Joe (voice), played by Jon Heder.
Reggie Belafonte (voice), played by James Woods.
Tank Evans (voice), played by Diedrich Bader.
Surf's Up is a 2007 American animated mockumentary sports comedy film directed by Ash Brannon
and Chris Buck, and written by Brannon, Buck, Don Rhymer and Chris Jenkins.
Produced by Sony Pictures Animation, the film features the voices of Shia
LaBeouf, Jeff Bridges, Zooey Deschanel, Jon Heder, and James Woods.
It is a parody of surfing documentaries, such as The Endless Summer and
Riding Giants, with parts of the plot parodying North Shore.
Real-life surfers Kelly Slater and Rob Machado have
vignettes as their penguin surfer counterparts.
To obtain the desired hand-held documentary feel, the film's animation
team motion-captured a physical camera operator's moves.
Surf's Up was released in the United States on June 8, 2007, by Sony Pictures Releasing, and received generally
positive reviews from critics, with praise for the animation, humor and unique mockumentary setup.
The film grossed $152 million against a budget of $100 million, and was
nominated for Best Animated Feature at the 80th Academy Awards.
A sequel, Surf's Up 2: WaveMania, was released in 2017.
A TV series is in development at Atomic Cartoons.
The film explores themes of sea, surfer, surfboard, wave, world cup.
The tone is lighthearted.